coolwinks.com 2019-09-04

# Privacy Policy - Coolwinks | www.coolwinks.com

We believe trust is everything. Hence, we follow the highest standards for securing all transactions and customer information privacy. Please read below to learn about our data/information collection and sharing practices.

### Important Note:

Our privacy policy is subject to change at any time without notice at the discretion of the management. Do make sure you are aware of any changes by reviewing this policy periodically.

By visiting this website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree please do not use or access our website.

By using our website, you express consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the Terms of Use.

###  Collection of Personally Identifiable Information and Other Information

When you use our website, we collect and store your personal information which is provided by you from time to time. We do this to ensure you have a safe, efficient, smooth and customized experience. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our website to make your experience safer and easier. In this process, we collect personal information from you that we consider necessary for achieving this purpose.

In general, you can browse the website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. Once you give us your personal information, you are not anonymous to us. Where possible, we indicate which fields are required to fill and which ones are optional. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular service or feature on the website. We may automatically track certain information about you based upon your behaviour on our website. We use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand, protect and serve our users. This information is compiled and analysed on an aggregate basis.

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of the website to help analyse our web page flow, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. "Cookies" are small files placed on your browser that assist us in providing our services.

Additionally, you may encounter "cookies" or other similar devices on certain pages of the website that are placed by third parties. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties.

If you choose to buy on the website, we collect information about your buying behaviour.

If you transact with us, we collect some additional information, such as a billing address, a credit / debit card number and a credit / debit card expiration date and/ or other payment instrument details and tracking information from cheques or money orders.

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the website, we may collect such information into a file specific to you.

We collect personally identifiable information (email address, name, phone number, credit card / debit card / other payment instrument details, etc.) from you when you set up a free account with us. While you can browse some sections of our website without being a registered member, certain activities (such as placing an order) do require registration. We do use your contact information to send you offers based on your previous orders and your interests.

If you allow us to access your contacts, it enables us to provide a lot of social features to you such as sharing your selected product with your friends, inviting your friends to try our app, send across referral links to your friends, etc. This information will be stored on our servers and synced from your phone.

###  Cookies

A "cookie" is a small piece of information stored by a web server on a web browser, so it can be accessed back from that browser. Cookies are useful for enabling the browser to remember information specific to a given user. We place both permanent and temporary cookies in your computer's hard drive. The cookies do not contain any of your personally identifiable information.

###  Sharing of Personal Information

We may share personal information with our other corporate entities and affiliates. These entities and affiliates may market to you as a result of such sharing unless you explicitly opt-out.

We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process. We may disclose personal information to law enforcement offices, third party rights owners or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: enforce our Terms or Privacy Policy; respond to claims that an advertisement, posting or other content violates the rights of a third party; or protect the rights, property or personal safety of our users or the general public.

We and our affiliates will share / sell some or all of your personal information with another business entity should we (or our assets) plan to merge with, or be acquired by that business entity, or re-organization, amalgamation, restructuring of business. Should such a transaction occur that other business entity (or the new combined entity) will be required to follow this privacy policy with respect to your personal information.

###  Links to Other Sites

Our website links to other websites that may collect personally identifiable information about you. Coolwinks.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those linked websites.

###  Security Precautions

Our Website has stringent security measures in place to avoid any loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Whenever you change or access your account information, we offer the use of a secure server. Once your information is in our possession we adhere to strict security guidelines, protecting it against unauthorized access.

###  Choice/Opt-Out

We provide all users with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving non-essential (promotional, marketing-related) communications from us on behalf of our partners, and from us in general, after setting up an account.

If you want to remove your contact information from all Coolwinks.com lists and newsletters, please visit unsubscribe.

###  Your Consent

By using the website and/ or by providing your information, you are giving consent to the collection and use of the information you disclose on the website in accordance with our Privacy Policy, including but not limited to your consent for sharing your information as per this privacy policy.

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

### App Permissions

We do require certain permissions to give you an effortless experience while shopping with us -

1\. **Location** \- To enhance your locale experience & show you personalized content as per your location. (From checking the availability of the product in your area to the delivery options available near you). 

2\. **SMS** \- To help us read text messages (SMS or MMS) or necessary push notifications, one-time passwords (OTPs) & confirm power that you’ve submitted. 

3\. **Phone** \- To read phone status & identity. 

4\. **Read Contacts** \- To get your phone number for billing purposes.

5\. **Camera** – To help you upload eye prescriptions directly from your phone.

### Grievance Officer

In accordance with Information Technology Act 2000 and rules made there under, the name and contact details of the Grievance Officer are provided below:

**Mr. Manish Kumar  
Coolwinks Technologies Private Limited.   
Plot A-8, Infocity 1, Sector 34  
Gurugram, Haryana 122001  
India  
Phone: +91 - 124-444-5800  
Email: support@coolwinks.com**
